Mukesh Manral

Data Scientist - CloudyML

■ mukeshmanral777@gmail.com \$\square\$ 8384801974 \$\overline{

Profile

2+ years of experience in data science and analytics. Worked with service-based startup as well as product-based startup and played a big role in scaleup of data science and analytics team along with the business.

Technical Skills

• Python • Machine Learning • Deep Learning • Computer Vision • AWS • AWS Sagemaker • Streamlit • Pandas • Numpy • scikit-learn • tensor-flow • keras • opency

Professional Experience

Data Scientist, CloudyML ∂

June 2021 - present

- Communicated effectively with team and external stakeholders.
- Created roadmaps for various data related courses and helped in launching.
- Participated in brainstorming and solutioning with the team and stakeholders.
- Facilitated data cleansing, enrichment and data quality improvements.
- Analysed and organized raw data.
- Have delivered complete product maketing reports to CEO and CMO in a very short span of time which was urgent and used efficiently in creating annual operation plans for various segments.
- Helped other stakeholders like the Marketing and growth product team to hire the right Analyst based on various use cases.

Project-1: Customer Life Time Value Prediction

- Extracted and Preprocessed only required records.
- Created impacting Features.
- Selected only required Features based on problem statement.
- Decreased churning customers rate by 4%.
- Increased future sales by 2.6%

Machine Learning Engineer, TechSim+

January 2020 – December 2020

Client : One Financial Corporation Project-1 : Loan Underwriting

- Preprocessed entire dataset and Selected most important 30 features.
- Boosted model efficiency by almost 5%.
- Validated model efficiency using matrix like classification Reports, confusion matrix, AUC Sscore.

Project-2: Customer Churn Prediction

- Preprocessed data and Performed Feature selection.
- Decreased churn rate by 2%
- Purposed different marking scheams as to retain churning customer

Certification

Master Data Science for Industry-(Ascend Pro), Link: ∅

November 2020 -October 2021

- Attended 12 Months Training on Full Stack Data Science for Industry
 - Institute: Analytics Vidhya

Got exposure to following areas of Data Science:

- Tools like Python, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikitlearn, Keras, Tableau, MongoDB, SQL, Spacy, Spark, AWS.
- Industry like Cusumer Market and Telecom, Financial Services, Life Science and Farma.

Machine Learning by Stanford University (Coursera),

May 2020 - July 2020

Link: ⊘

Achievements

Machine Hack Data Hackon, Link: ∅

Global Ranking of 315

Kaggle, Link: ∂

Pain Point: Like others I have to invested a ton of time and money in exploring Machine Learning and Deep Learning

AIM: To make easy to follow Machine Learning and Deep Learning framework in simple words Written easy to follow kernels on different Machine Learning Algorithms and Deep Learning

Github, Link: 🔗

Sharing my knowledge with Data Science community

Education

Bachelor's in Computer Science Engineering, Uttarakhand Technical University

June 2015 - July 2019